SHRUTI CHATURVEDI

CONTACT

- (+91) 790-517-5420
- (+1) 269-548-5390

LINK TO WEBSITE:

https://developershruti.web.app

LINK TO ACCLAIM-PROFILE:

https://www.youracclaim.com/us

ers/shruti-chaturvedi

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shru

ti-chaturvedi-developer/

PROFILE

Inquisitive, enthusiastic, and a challenge-driven entry-level software engineer, with specialized interest in cloud-based Developer Infrastructure Operations; front-end and server-side development; Data Analysis and Engineering with Python.

I deeply value learning, and am always willing to **educate and challenge** myself. I bring an **analytical**, **investigative**, **creative and tenacious problem-solving energy** to the workplace.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & BADGES

- ORACLE CLOUD
- MEARN JS STACK: MONGODB,
 EXPRESS, ANGULAR, REACT,
 NODE IS
- REACT-NATIVE APP
 DEVELOPMENT
- AUTOMATION W/ PYTHON
- DOCKER CONTAINERIZATION
- OPENSHIFT ORCHESTRATION
- DATA ANALYSIS W/ PYTHON
- SERVER DEVELOPMENT W/ PYTHON & EXPRESS

EXPERIENCE

Public Policy Intern, YWCA, Michigan

April, 2020 - July, 2020

Researched and gathered data on public policy implementations across the country.

Used **Python's SEABORN** library to visualize analytical and statistical educational data throughout Michigan.

Ran **Mongo's GeoSpatial** queries on MongoDB to categorize schools depending upon the racial markup.

Teaching Assistant for Computer Science, Western Michigan University & Kalamazoo College, Michigan

Instructed students on facets of Java, Python, C, Javascript, MySQL, register and memory management, computer algorithms, and other relevant technology.

Prepared and updated webpages for course materials.

Updated class-servers from JSON-servers to express-servers

Undergraduate Research Intern, Kalamazoo College

- VERSION CONTROL W/ GIT
- CLOUD ENGINEERING IN GOOGLE CLOUD PLATFORM

September, 2019 - 2020

Researched how we can accomplish sentiment analysis from unlabeled images though a Deep Neural Network developed and trained using TensorFlow.

Researched on a service which will be able to analyze if a system/data collection is inherently biased by comparing two similar images and then comparing the sentiment of the images. It would help design better solutions for criminal justice systems.

EDUCATION

Kalamazoo College, Michigan, US

2018-

Bachelors of Science in Engineering

SPSEC, Kanpur, India

2003 - 2017

Graduated in 2017, with an aggregate percentage of 95%, with individual score of 95 in Math, Physics, Chemistry, and Computer Science each.

RECENT TECHNICAL CERTS

- 1. ORACLE CLOUD ARCHITECT PROFESSIONAL
- 2. ORACLE CLOUD DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE
- 3. ORACLE CLOUD OPERATIONS ASSOCIATE
- 4. ORACLE CLOUD ARCHITECT ASSOCIATE
- 5. PYTHON FOR OS

VERIFY THEM HERE:

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/220f3ad3-dfe0-4303-9a24-ba72fbb6186c/public url

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/1b8390be-93aa-45f4-b8fe-e9eebfddb9e9/public_url

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/d93ceedf-bd82-4a92-9f73-4c6957eca396/public_url

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/81aa0f6d-ec98-4c87-9e2a-666ea4210adb/public_url

https://coursera.org/share/68d3bbb1e35c294c48c7002676b11fd4

HONORS, AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Honors Award for outstanding performance in Computer Science, Kalamazoo College

Dean's List for 2018-19, Kalamazoo College

Recipient, H.P and Genevieve Connable Faculty-nominated Fund for Physics

Research Grant for assisting the analysis of asset exchange model or income inequity, using Open Simulation Pattern libraries.

Recipient, Lux Esto Award, Kalamazoo College

Recipient, Van Dalson Scholarship Award, Kalamazoo College

Recipient, President's Grant Award, Kalamazoo College